Eduardo Iotti

Senior Software Engineer (Front-end, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Angular, Vue, Next.js)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/eduardoiotti/ | https://github.com/dudouz

Senior software engineer based in Brazil, with 6+ years of experience with front-end development and 10+ years of experience in the web industry.

I have been developing and delivering web apps, using TypeScript and React, together with front-end frameworks such as NextJS.

For 6 years until now, I've focused on software engineering and had the opportunity to work on several projects/companies as a front-end developer, such as Brazilian e-commerce heavy players - Via Varejo, PetLove, DogHero, Webmotors, and New York-based Prescriptive Data's game changer real state monitoring system - NantumOS.

Currently leading a front-end team of 3 engineers, for an early-stage startup called Scalis, and still getting hands-on code using state-of-the-art techs: NextJS 14, Tailwind, RadixUI, Zod and React Hook Forms, and React Query/Apollo, integrating with GraphQL and Rest APIs.

Work Experience:

- > Scalis Lead Front-end engineer
 August 2024 Now. Miami, FL USA
 - Led a team of 3 front-end engineers, advocating for code quality, organization, and delivery cadence.
 - Contributed as a front-end engineer for an AI-driven ATS software, using state-of-the-art technologies such as NextJS 14 Tailwind, RadixUI, React Query, and PrismaDB, delivered Job Requisition Modules, integrated with GraphQL APIs.
 - Maintained a complex component library within Storybook platform, leveraging Tailwind Variants and previously defined design tokens to allow core component extension and reutilization over the app, most of the time following the atomic design philosophy.
 - Managed backlog and proposed product roadmap strategies, introducing agile concepts to a previously unorganized team such as daily stand-ups, refinement sessions, and guild meetings, aiming for team building and clear objective alignment.

- > Softensity Senior Front-end developer.
 October 2022 August 2024. Marietta, GA USA
 - Worked as a consultant engineer for Softensity, an American outsourcing company based in Georgia.
 - Lead front-end community, conducting 1x1's and keeping track of 10+ engineers and their project status, making reports to higher level management team.
 - Contributed as a front-end engineer for a Smart Buildings / Real State Management Software called Nantum OS, from Prescriptive Data, a company based in New York, delivering modules related to keeping track and displaying sensor data over the app
 - Improved Nantum OS app performance by upgrading core libraries such as Webpack (from v4 to v5), React (from v17 to v18), moving from 8 to 10 minutes build time to 3 minutes build time and reaching over 500% hot module reloading time improvement (from 1 to 3 minutes to 10s)
 - Contributed as a front-end engineer for a B2B employee relation software called Happy Orbit, from Gravitational Marketing, a digital marketing agency based in Florida.
 - Created visual components and interfaces using React, SCSS, and TypeScript.
 - Delivered three complex modules for the MVP: Board Game, Catalog Management, and a fully manageable Quiz module.
 - Worked with a pre-built component library called BlueprintJS
 - Tested user interface components using StoryBook
 - Presented an AI LLM-driven chatbot built with Python and Langchain on an internal contest for artificial intelligence-based products.
 - Assured clean coding standards through code reviews, git flow, and core engineering principles such as SOLID, KISS, DRY, and YAGNI.
- > petlove&co Senior Front-end engineer. December 2020 - October 2022. São Paulo - Brazil
 - Worked at PetLove, a huge e-commerce ecosystem for pets based in Brazil, as a Specialist front-end engineer.
 - Refactored legacy Angular-based platform into Vue/Nuxt-based tech at the DogHero business unit.
 - Applied micro front-end architecture, splitting the legacy code into separate applications.
 - Used monorepo structure with Turborepo for clustering different apps into one GitHub repo and leveraging on reusable and shareable components.

- Managed state through a full-refactored checkout flow moving from Vuex to Pinia.
- Tested components at unit level with Jest and E2E with Playwright.
- Delivered a business unit home page in less than 2 months, adapting WindiCSS to the existing company-provided design system.
- Achieved better organic search engine results at the SEO/Growth team, mostly by optimizing performance and other aspects of Google's core web vitals.
- Published applications through automated CI/CD pipelines using Codefresh, Jenkins, and Google Cloud Platform.
- Monitored app performance and failures with Honeybadger and Datadog.

> via Mid Front-end engineer. February 2020 - December 2020. São Paulo - Brazil

- Worked at Via, one of the biggest retail e-commerce from Brazil, as a mid-front-end developer.
- Delivered a brand-new payment method in a short-term period (2 months or less), using state-of-the-art React + NextJS stack.
- Created React components that would adapt to each business unit's aesthetics standards with Styled Components and Styled System variations.
- Maintained the legacy AngularJS mobile site storefront, built with Pug/Jade SCSS preprocessor.
- Monitored apps through regular stress tests, preparing for big events such as black-Friday, using Grafana and Dynatrace.
- Published apps through automated CI/CD pipelines with complex approval flows, using XL Release and Jenkins.
- Created a new storefront MVP using a pre-build component library called Chakra UI and styling it with Emotion.
- Managed state for React applications using Redux and Redux-Saga.
- > webmotors Front-end engineer. January 2019 - February 2020. Florianópolis - Santa Catarina, Brazil
 - Worked on a B2B product called More Loyalty as an entry-level front-end engineer.
 - Unblocked three React Apps that were left not functioning by the previous team in less than a month of work.
 - Followed Atomic Design pattern for creating and managing components inside the applications.
 - Managed state for the applications using Redux Reducer/Action patterns.
 - Used BitBucket for version and release management.

> previous experiences Before 2019

- Delivered 60+ WordPress website projects during a 5+ year freelance career (2011-2016).
- Worked as a User Interface Designer for three years: 2008-2011.
- Crafted +50 graphic design projects including logos, brochures, and posters.

- Led a 2 employees team when started a small design bureau (2016-2018).
- Designed a handful of Adobe Flash animations using pure ActionScript code.

Education History:

degrees

- MBA in Software Engineering (PUC-Rio / 2023-2024)
- Nanodegree in Digital Marketing (Udacity / 2018-2019)
- Bachelor of Arts in Advertising (UCS / 2006-2011)

certifications

- Clean Architecture Rodrigo Branas 2022
- Software Architecture Full Cycle 2022
- Continuous Integration Full Cycle 2022
- Domain-Driven Design Full Cycle 2021
- Docker Full Cycle 2021
- Advanced GitHub Full Cycle 2021
- NextJS and React Cod3r 2021
- JavaScript Functional Programming Cod3r 2021
- React Certification Test Dome 2021
- Human-Computer Interaction IDF 2020
- Gatsby And React Apps Udemy 2020
- FullStack JS Bootcamp. Rocketseat 2019